<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE feature_key_file [
   <!ELEMENT feature_key_file (comments, feature+)>
   <!ELEMENT comments (#PCDATA)>
   <!ELEMENT feature (name, description?, is_sequential, parallel_dimensions)>
   <!ELEMENT name (#PCDATA)>
   <!ELEMENT description (#PCDATA)>
   <!ELEMENT is_sequential (#PCDATA)>
   <!ELEMENT parallel_dimensions (#PCDATA)>
]>

<feature_key_file>

   <comments></comments>

   <feature>
      <name>Basic Pitch Histogram</name>
      <description>A feature vector consisting of bin magnitudes of the basic pitch histogram described in the jSymbolic manual. Each bin corresponds to one of the 128 MIDI pitches, ordered from lowest to highest, and with an interval of a semitone between each (enharmonic equivalents are assigned the same pitch number). Bin 60 corresponds to middle C. The magnitude of of each bin is proportional to the the number of times notes occurred at the bin's pitch in the piece, relative to all other pitches in the piece (the histogram is normalized).</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>128</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Number of Pitches</name>
      <description>Number of unique pitches that occur at least once in the piece. Enharmonic equivalents are grouped together for the purpose of this calculation.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Number of Pitch Classes</name>
      <description>Number of pitch classes that occur at least once in the piece. Enharmonic equivalents are grouped together for the purpose of this calculation.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Range</name>
      <description>Difference in semitones between the highest and lowest pitches.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Strong Tonal Centres</name>
      <description>Number of isolated peaks in the fifths pitch histogram that each individually account for at least 9% of all notes in the piece.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Mean Pitch</name>
      <description>Mean MIDI pitch value, averaged across all pitched notes in the piece. Set to 0 if there are no pitched notes.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Mean Pitch Class</name>
      <description>Mean pitch class value, averaged across all pitched notes in the piece. A value of 0 corresponds to a mean pitch class of C, and pitches increase chromatically by semitone in integer units from there (e.g. a value of 2 would mean that D is the mean pitch class). Enharmonic equivalents are treated as a single pitch class.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Most Common Pitch</name>
      <description>MIDI pitch value of the most frequently occuring pitch.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Most Common Pitch Class</name>
      <description>The pitch class that occurs most frequently compared to other pitch classes. A value of 0 corresponds to C, and pitches increase chromatically by semitone in integer untis (e.g. a value of 2 would mean that D is the most common pitch class). Enharmonic equivalents are treated as a single pitch class.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Interval Between Most Prevalent Pitches</name>
      <description>Absolute value of the difference (in semitones) between the pitches of the two most frequently occurring pitches.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Interval Between Most Prevalent Pitch Classes</name>
      <description>Absolute value of the difference (in semitones) between the pitches of the two most frequently occurring pitch classes.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Pitch Variability</name>
      <description>Standard deviation of the MIDI pitches of all pitched notes in the piece. Provides a measure of how close the pitches as a whole are to the mean pitch.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Most Common Melodic Interval</name>
      <description>Number of semitones corresponding to the most frequently occurring melodic interval.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

</feature_key_file>